hello and welcome to storyboard I'm
Shabani garat in a special chat we are
catching up with Laura halsworth
managing director Asia Pacific
booking.com she was visiting Delhi this
week she's meeting us and speaking to us
about the developments in travel and the
sentiment of Travelers their key
Investments going forward expectations
from 2024 and much more Laura welcome to
CNBC TV8 thank you very much for having
me what are some of the key travel
trends that youve witnessed so far in
the year
Laura well we're seeing that travel
remains incredibly resilient which is
good for all of us in the industry we're
seeing that worldwide and we're
certainly seeing it across Asia Pacific
and increasingly so or so across India
um we've seen we've had record numbers
for the last two years when we think you
know there was initial sense of Revenge
travel um in 2022 we saw globally 900
million room kns booked last year we saw
over a billion and we expect to continue
to see a rise of that this year uh even
in the start of the year we are seeing
travel the bookings that we've got
already for the rest of the year are
significantly higher than they were this
time last year so we know that travel is
certainly here to stay um and we see
that Travelers are continuing to
prioritize their discretionary spend on
travel so again it's good news I think
for all of us across the industry
upcoming weeks and upcoming months are
critical for travel portals such as
yours your expectations from the
upcoming spring and summer
Laura yeah I think we can continue to
see I say we've broken records the last
two summers uh we expect to probably see
the same this year already we can see
significant uh bookings already made
certainly for Peak periods uh and
luckily for us across Asia Pacific those
Peak periods are quite spread out uh and
so we don't rely heavily on only a
summer period but as you say there
spring there's a lot of kind of the
religious and spiritual periods that we
have to take advantage of so I think
across the region we will expect to see
continued strength in numbers all
throughout the year yes and we have seen
an increase in the Indian users going to
booking.com and doing their hotel uh
reservations uh what are some of the
opportunities
and you know what are some of the things
uh that the platform sees as lucrative
and willing to invest in the country in
particular absolutely I mean I think the
whole world and not just booking.com the
whole world is looking at the India
traveler the rise of this with a largest
world's largest population and certainly
a fastest rising middle class we know
that the the market is going to grow
from 200 150 million dolls in 2019 to
410 billion in 2030 so there's a huge
opportunity for everybody in travel
space to capture this demand and make
sure that we're meeting Travelers where
they need us the most so for us
certainly at booking.com and across the
booking Brands um we continue to invest
as I mentioned in the domestic traveler
so making sure that we have the the
types of accommodation that those
Travelers are looking for and that tends
to be beyond the Metro cities now um so
we're looking at tier two tier three
cities we're looking at locations such
as varasi coochi myau for the religious
and spiritual travel um and also I
talked about the kind of wedding tourism
we know that that's also taking place in
the smaller regions so also bringing a
lot of opportunities to growth in jobs
so we will continue to try and meet our
Travelers where they need us um we have
teams on the ground all across India to
make sure that we're providing the the
right types of accommodation we've got
over 7,000 listings now across the um
across India an increasing rise in
alternative accommodation so outside of
the core properties um we're seeing much
more and we've got about 14 different
types of properties now listed um as
well as obviously we've put in um
additional language support so we've
launched Hindi last year uh and the
other investment that we've made into
this very critical Market is our Center
of Excellence which supports all of the
booking do booking Holdings Brands uh
and that's a $250 million investment
we've made over the next five years
around thousand jobs in Bangalore so
we're excited to see what that can bring
we know the talent is very strong uh
here in India and so we continue to
invest okay and also in terms of
marketing events what are some of the
things that you have your eyes on to
advertise last year you deployed a
sizeable amount of budget towards
Cricket so will that investment in
sports sponsorships and Cricket continue
going forward as
well yeah we continue to look for where
the opportunities are again where
Travelers need us where we will raise
the most amount of awareness yes we
sponsored the ICC world cricket both
men's and women's over the last five
years um and we were able to get a lot
of coverage but also enable ourselves to
work with brand ambassadors like Rohit
Sharma so we really wanted to work
closely with what who's relevant here in
the market and we will continue to look
for what's next for us um going forward
for this Market how are the shifts in
technology shaping your strategies going
forward how do you specifically Envision
uh generative AI transforming the travel
industry oh it will for sure like every
industry I think travel is not unique in
that sense and actually within
booking.com we've been using AI machine
learning for a very long time in in ways
that we help to find the right searches
for you whether we could optimize our
Google searches so we've been using it
for a long time but now I think seeing
it through generative AI um and the
opportunities that that brings for
travelers to interact in exactly the way
that they want we talk about
personalization this is the ultimate
opportunity for full personalization for
a traveler to look for the preferences
that they have based on their their past
but also n engaging with us in natural
language um and allowing us to provide
inspirational travel opportunities um as
well as take travelers to what they they
already know so it's it is
transformative um booking.com is already
on the way as I mentioned the trip
planner and I think we will just
continue to see the rise of the use of
this type of Technology um for travelers
to improve the service all the time it
is time for a short break on the other
side we have Tom Newton Global CEO
conand Design Group and ANZ Gman mutus
Sami strategy managing director W con
brand design
speaking welcome back how group this
week has mered mer its two design
specialist agencies conran Design Group
with paris-based agency W to consolidate
and create the Conrad Design Group
Network this new network will focus on
brand and Design Services the global
roll out of Conrad design was initiated
from India around the announcement the
network also marked the release of
conand design groups New proprietary
studies citizen Brands which identifies
brands that are achieving balanced
growth the study also found the top 20
citizen Brands those who were able to
meet the needs of both individuals and
society as per the report the top 10
citizen brands in India are Google Tata
Amazon Samsung Microsoft tataa Motors
Apple Sony LG and PTM to tell us more
about the insights from this report and
also about the formation of the new
network we are joined in by Tom Newton
Global CEO conran Design Group and ANZ
giman mut Sami strategy managing
director W Conrad design so this will
bring two agencies design agencies uh
Under One Roof which is of course W and
conran uh together and the roll out is
happening out of India yes uh tell us
the reason uh to for this roll out to
happen out of the country well I mean we
set up our business here in Mumbai in
right in the middle of lockdown 2021
that's right so everything was virtual
yeah um all of the hiring and the team
was put together virtually and it it
felt like a sort of risky thing to do at
the time uh actually the momentum and
the traction the interest in design uh
and the connection to the conran Design
Group brand we felt straight away here
in India there was a real appetite for
design and brand um and a real
entrepreneurial Spirit actually I think
in the region so it was a very positive
experience we had very good momentum and
it just felt very natural to launch the
Network here you know we we're
absolutely convinced and you know
committed to Mumbai and India being one
of our key Global hubs as we grow and
for us this was never an exercise about
pins in the map you know we never
intended and we don't intend to have 60
70 offices that's not our model we want
six or seven worldclass offerings dotted
around the world and India will be one
and is we have you with us today tell us
more about you know some of the insights
from the citizens brand report that you
have launched so thank you for asking
this question it was important for us to
have a piece a study something to build
upon our capability to address nowadays
needs and expectation and basically what
we've done is look at brands in an
nistic approach so we've looked at
investors brand leaders but at the same
time public opinion in five different
markets so India the US the UK France
and Saudi Arabia and what we wanted to
know is what was expected and how could
brand leaders grow in a balanced way and
what we found is that brands should um
act upon a new kind of compass uh this
Compass must address individual needs
that we know betterment
originality Assurance but at the same
time societal needs like inclusion
environmentalism and contribution to
society as large so it has been really
interesting to look into it and to see
that actually by being a balanced brand
a citizen brand addressing both society
and individual what you can deliver is
growth reputational growth by basically
addressing and attracting new talents
and retaining them but also bringing new
appetite for your products and for your
Serv
okay what apart from you know addressing
the society and people do these uh
brands that feature really high up in
the citizen brand report have in common
according to un it's it's quite
interesting because there is a lot of
things that are asked to to the brands
we call it the expectation inflation
what is that exactly very interesting
term yeah actually it's some kind of of
strange era we are all part of like you
can feel it we are asking more and more
to leaders if you look at what
Regulators are asking what citizen are
asking what employees are asking what
customers are asking and also investors
stakeholders everyone is asking for
something and this expectation are not
always in line one with another so
that's why we've coined this world the
expectation inflation uh era is that
basically it's really difficult to see
where you should Del
on the long term as a brand leaders and
actually when we've asked investors and
brand leaders they they were telling us
that they were working a sort of
reputational tight rope yes they are in
under a lot of pressure and basically it
was about 94% of them telling us that
they were feeling that they were fearing
to be perceived as not doing enough in
terms of societal impact and I at the
same time almost 90% of them were saying
they were fearing also to be perceived
as to woke yeah meaning that it's
difficult to handle this kind of
pressure and this why this is why we
needed some kind of new Compass to
address what is as from so how do they
do that how do they balance it out
that's a very interesting thought that
you just shared like not appearing to
walk at the same time they need to
appear that they're doing something yeah
for the society it it's it's kind of
interesting what we find is that in the
top brands they mainly uh deliver you
can see that say all deliver regarding
Assurance so they are well-known trusted
brands that bring Assurance in the world
where trust is really hard and difficult
to to to build and at the same time they
have their own Mark they have their own
set of goals and so they they have their
own way to addressing this Compass uh by
making most of the time also inclusion a
part of their brand building something
really important for them and this is
why we see at the top of the brand index
a lot of the tech consumer Tech uh
brands that are well performing in both
aspects inclusion and at the same time
Assurance my final question to both of
you is uh what are some of the biggest
mistakes that uh you know Brands make
while uh let's say creating a brand or
you know like setting up a new or
establishing a new brand or you know
sometimes undergoing a brand revamp for
that matter let's begin with you with
anise yeah I I I would say that
obviously you have to have a different
product or different services and that's
already a lot to to achieve but at the
same time more and more and that's we
what we see in citizen brand is that you
have to have a point of view you have a
point you have to have a point of view
as a brand regarding Society at large
and to make sure that you have a
relevant role to play in this Society
according to your point of view and
maybe once you have that once you have
this foundation for me it's all about
delivering it by Design also believing
in uh Tom yeah I Echo um an A's point I
think many organizations sometimes view
growth as a as a zero sum game you have
to trade one thing for another thing we
would argue that
balance um and you know this the whole
the whole purpose of the citizen brand
study was to think longer term think
that progress has to carry everyone
forward you don't have to trade off one
audience for another uh or one
commercial ambition for more of a
societal sense of responsibility you can
use the levers to balance those things
and that will give you longevity will
connect more profoundly with audiences
sure and it will set you up for
long-term growth and I think you know
the examples we've SE of businesses in
different markets different regions
failing is because they don't take a
long-term view they don't play the long
game they chase Dynamic short-term
growth without being prepared and having
their brand prepared for the longer term
great thank you so much thanks for
joining us today thanks for sh than
thanks for having us it is time for a
short break on the other side we have
shea Kapoor head marketing corporate
Communications and CSR ICI Lombard
speaking about their
ICI Lombard has introduced a very
Innovative integrated media initiative
called Game of Life this pioneering
Concept in the insurance domain combines
the excitement of gaming with the
practicality of insurance this campaign
leverages the captivating Allure of
virtual games to connect with the
digital native generation while speaking
about the uncertainties and ups and
downs of our everyday life while urging
the viewers to stay protected to tell us
more we are joined in by Sheena capur
head marketing corporate Communications
and CSR ICI Lombard Shea welcome to CNBC
TV8 thank you so much and it's pleasure
to be here China first of all game of
life I saw the campaign such an
interesting concept tell us more about
it how it was conceptualized what were
some of the discussions that you had
with your agency oal V I believe um and
what was the kind of brief that you gave
to them for us game of life has been a
very uh disruptive campaign and uh as
always you know with any bfsi sector Q4
happens to be like the most active uh
season and uh we started actually
thinking and ideating about scripts uh
way back in uh Q3 about October November
so that we're you know well in time
ready uh with the plan and uh we
actually went through through some six
to seven very interesting scripts um and
we looked at different kind of
narratives uh we were sure that we
wanted to talk about something which was
at a brand level which was at an
corporate level uh a campaign that spoke
about icsl Lombard but spoke about a
different tonality and spoke about the
category uh we wanted to have something
which was a culmination of uh technology
um ideation uh
creativity uh Innovation and uh is yet
very engaging um you know for the
viewers especially something that
engages and appeals to the younger
audience the Millennials and the Gen Z
and gamification so how did you arrive
upon gamifying uh you know to
communicate the objective of buying an
insurance Life's a game you really don't
know what will happen next it's so
uncertain you can't really predict
because it is unpredictable um and
insurance therefore you know as a
category we're there uh to be um you
know providing that shield and that
protection uh cover for the consumers
across whether it's you know health
insurance or whether it's motor
insurance uh to safeguard the consumers
um you know against these kind of
uncertainties as well as protecting the
assets um and so we asked ourselves okay
here is this gamification route can we
bring alive the entire concept and bring
in in the environment of gaming so that
we make it even more cooler and we make
it more engaging and uh you know and I
think it's resonated uh very well of
course with the younger audience but I'm
happy to say that that even uh with the
older demographics it has resonated
really well so having said that I'm
tempted to ask what has it done for ICI
Lombard uh or what can it potentially do
for the brand as compared to what you
know the traditional uh campaign would
have done so you know um again this is
far removed from anywhere close to what
traditional uh has done so far and in
fact arguably uh not just within the
insurance not even within the bfsi I'm
saying across categories um and i' I'd
go bold enough to say within India and
arguably even across the world this is
the first time any brand has attempted a
narrative which is using
a gaming environment and uh the
production house the creative agencies
the director has pulled this off so
fabulously that it actually looks like
robotic characters when they're actually
humans who are uh portraying the entire
film narrative um and through the film
like I said you know we have spoken
about um you know the different aspects
of life and we've brought up the analogy
with health bar or the power bar like
you have in a game so anything that you
do which is um you know um which could
leave you wable uh to any kind of mishap
or is actually you know taking away from
your well-being actually depletes your
energy so you reaching out for junk food
even though you know that a healthier
choice exists uh is actually not doing
too you know too great for you in the
health terms in the longer run right um
and that's what we're trying to also
Advocate to the audience saying
preventive uh health care and the
overall well-being and the Continuum of
Care that we want to propose um and as
against any kind of traditional adwar
you would have possibly taken a product
you know exemplified the features or um
you know the Contours of the product or
you know as as a lot of brands do you
know engage with even ROP in some
celebrities you know to uh pull off the
narrative this is you know extremely
differentiated uh disruptive original
and very very refreshing in fact I have
been I think the best form of uh you
know uh you know compliment that one can
receive is from the competition itself
you know and from the a lot of the
marketeers you know from within the
insurance and bfsi category uh they've
come forward to you know congratulate uh
us on the campaign and have been saying
that you know this has really raised the
bar uh from and otherwise a very boring
category which is uh which is kind of
you know used to doing some boring work
and not like very disruptive work thank
you so much thanks for joining us today
and thanks for sharing these insights
with us she thank you thank you so
much